so we're talking about knapsack coin
joins today I'm just going to run
through this slide and then hopefully
Felix will jump in to clarify questions
as they come or if I make a mistake so
yeah this is the paper anonymous cordial
transaction with arbitrary values we
have one of the author's with us the
PowerPoint this PowerPoint will be of
made available if anyone wants it very
straightforward so what's the problem in
Bitcoin transactions are public
transactions point to previous
transactions in a sort of directed
acyclic graph and transactions can leak
future spending that's that's that's the
problem we're trying to obfuscate the
transaction graph so a simple idea from
2013 or even earlier is just joining
transactions so suppose you have two
transactions on the left here we have
two transactions with two inputs and two
outputs 1 output is likely sending money
somewhere and another output is change
we could simply do is we could take
transactions and we could just
essentially collapse them together so
there's nothing in Bitcoin that bars us
from doing this currently at the moment
and yeah so how does this look like on
our left we have two unique transactions
by two individuals and I've highlighted
it in red
the output that likely represents
sending funds to a third party or to
others to someone else and on the right
what we do is we just take those inputs
and outputs and we merge them into a
single transaction now when we look at
this from the outside we have to ask
ourselves is it possible to to unravel
the previous transaction that we
the two sub transactions we merge
together so we can start by taking an
output like this one here
valued at fifty and we can try to find
inputs that exactly match the value of
the sum of the outputs so in this case
we try these two and it turns out
there's no way we could come up with an
output on the right that would match the
two inputs on the left and we try again
and we find that yes actually we can
break this transaction down into two
pieces once again because we see that
the bottom two inputs in the bottom two
outputs equal exactly 64 and the top two
inputs and two outputs exactly equal 33
we're excluding transaction fees in this
model for simplicity and so essentially
what happens is we take this this single
transaction and we split it into two
once again and we're left with the same
privacy that we would have had before we
did any of this joining so this isn't
very good so most of the time we'll be
able to unravel these transactions so if
we if we look at the work done by in
this paper what they've done is they
formalize some some basic ideas so you
know transactions have inputs outputs
and values inputs you know we have the
input set the output set and then we
have coins which belong either to the
inputs or the outputs and then a very
basic rule which is that the sum of the
inputs must equal the sum of the outputs
for any subset can we create so
according to a transaction consists of
sub transactions and there must be at
least one way of partitioning all inputs
and outputs so that each sub set of
inputs is exactly one corresponding sub
set of outputs with which it forms a sub
transactions and essentially what this
means is that if we take a transaction
we must be able to cut it up in such a
way just like we did before we're a
subset of the inputs matches some subset
of the outputs in terms of value
and we call this mapping as it Maps
inputs to outputs so we have a set of
all partitions denoted Phi of a set and
then the set of all inputs set of all
outputs and the set of all mappings is
again and essentially the set of all
mappings below here is just the set of
all I think it's by jected mappings of
inputs to outputs of the superset such
that the sum of the inputs equals a sign
of the outputs so again this is just
saying that we can take a transaction
and and create a list of all possible
ways we could cut it up essentially
figuring out different ways we could we
could get some transactions and the
entire list of all ways we could cut it
up is denoted him I hope I haven't lost
anyone so far but a good idea to maybe
pause and ask did have I lost anyone so
far no I think it's it's a great
introduction I just want to say for some
administration that since Felix appeared
in this in this conversation back on
Felix is one of the author of the paper
and I think after your presentation we
could move on to pick his brain and in
order to not waste his time too much and
and and then after that we can move on
to other people's presentations and
ideas and discussions about that yeah so
this is pretty much it almost over I
think we're probably two-thirds of the
way through so well will will to ask
Felix questions directly so yeah now
moving on to results
so yeah in simpler terms we want to be
able to break down transactions into sub
transactions a combination of inputs and
outputs in the paper they they clarify
between derived and non derived sub
transactions what that means is that a
non derived sub transaction is
is some transaction that isn't composed
of smaller sub transactions inside of it
and we're only concerned with non direct
sub transactions for simplicity so so
the way that we look at anonymity or
privacy in this model is we essentially
take a transaction which has all these
inputs outputs and it has all these
mappings all the possible ways we could
cut up the transaction and we
essentially say that a specific coin on
the left-hand side and any other coin on
the right-hand side or on the left hand
side is linked is linked to that coin in
a probability probabilistic way
depending on how many mappings of the
total mappings there are how many of
them include the two coins being in the
same sub transaction so I think there's
no way an easier way to think about this
here it is formalized in the paper but
non intuitively it makes a lot of sense
and I think we'll see an example of it
in just the next slide but that's the
idea it's a probabilistic framework so
in this case here if we go back and
recreate what we did and we split these
up into two sub transactions yeah we
would say that for example output 3 is
directly linked to input 3 with a
hundred percent probability because
there's only one way to partition this
coin join and output 3 appears with
input 3 a hundred percent of the time
and we'll see later how that can that
can be done differently so in the paper
they essentially create or create a
bunch of random transactions and then
essentially purposefully combine them
together
and then observe the time it takes to to
recreate the sub transactions from the
couple transaction solely you know here
we see that in the orange you know if
you have five sub transactions
I believe it's yeah so five sub
transactions with with four inputs each
that it takes about a second for a
computer to be able to unravel that in
that coin joining to it's relevant sub
transactions and then we notice here
that the number of non derived mappings
isn't very high even as there are you
know as many as you know four or five
sub transactions because when we did in
the first example we can typically
unravel coin joints and have a very
little overlap in terms of other other
ways we could map inputs and outputs so
the in here we see that only with six
sub transactions and four inputs per sub
transaction do we see more than just a
few non derived mappings so there's a
solution to this problem because right
now what we see is that it doesn't take
a lot of time to unpack these coin
joints and when you do there are very
few non derived mappings which means
there's very little ambiguity in terms
of what's linked so could we crease this
well you know here's a knapsack mixing
that is is how to optimize filling a
knapsack with various things of
different weights in this case we're
trying to optimize the way to have
output so that they fill given inputs so
the algorithm is pretty simple
the idea is to compare the two output
sets and to essentially try to break
down one of the outputs so that one of
the values of the output is that the
difference between the two sets so in
this case the number 31 is the
difference between the green and the
orange and so here we've done it with
you can see that we've split up the 50
into 31 19 and on
right we've recombined them to make a
single coin joy transaction and now when
we try to figure out the sub
transactions we actually get two sub
transactions we get this one here which
connects the two on the left with the
three on the right but we also get this
sub transaction here and so the result
is that if you asked for example this oh
one linked with I three the answer is
that there's a 50-50 chance that oh one
in I three are linked because of the two
sub transactions that we have in half of
them oh one and I three are not linked
and the other half they are the dialouge
you or you lost me
to have a probability of one we match
with another input or another outplay
yeah right so the left graph shows the
number of pairs of inputs and outputs
that are linked with probability one and
the right one shows the number of input
input pairs that are linked with the
probability of one always depending on
which knapsack mixing every when you've
used so I think in the paper I had two
different versions of the collapse like
mixing algorithm one which I called
input mixing and one output mixing and I
think I even hinted at a third one that
I came up with later in the in the time
when I was writing the paper so this one
even improved over what you see in the
Kraft so far okay well very cool so I
think the important things you know here
is that we still have a problem where
some inputs are connected with other
inputs and some inputs are connected
with other outputs so we don't have a
perfect we have some points that are
hard are achieving no additional and
anima d except for the computational
complexity that it takes to unravel the
the coin joint so this is pretty much
the ends here there's some anonymity
here in the computational complexity
that's required to to figure out how to
break down these coin joins especially
if we start talking about you know ten
participants 30 participants 50
participants there's still a link
between the inputs and outputs the
entire sub transaction petition must be
known in order to apply the algorithm
this is the most important trade-off I
think is that currently from what I've
read it seems that this can be done in a
net trustless way where someone isn't
coordinating all the transactions yeah
and that's exactly the third algorithm I
came up with
I will have to read my own work again to
understand what I did because it's or I
think two years now that I was working
on it but I had a third version of the
algorithm which was working without
knowing all the outputs so for each
everybody knows needs to know all the
inputs but each participant only needs
to know his own outputs okay so would it
be everybody just needs to know all the
inputs okay
so interesting so upper bound and nobody
it's you know like if we look at this
way of looking at transaction anonymity
and we applied to zero link we see that
zero link is like a perfect knapsack
coin joint so that sort of provides us
the upper bound anonymity which is
essentially the number of total
participants that are doing this this
knapsack coin joint a lot of things here
and I think this is your your last slide
so can I come back to it later and
discuss everything every concluding
thought one by one sure sure
so yeah only to Felix because that's
pretty much deal have you seen the paper
Thank You Aviv it's it's a nice
introduction to get everyone catch up
with the paper and we can go into the
details here and there I was thinking
that if Felix appears then we would we
would start with some questions to Felix
and then we would continue with the if
anyone has some small presentations then
then we would continue with those and
then we would end up with discussions
questions what did we not understood in
the in the paper
although this could be bring-bring here
right now because felix is still here so
and we would finally discuss some some
things like like if you have any ideas
that came to your mind with this paper
and then we would envy dirties and we
deciding on what should be the next
paper on next week so let's start with
let's start with some some more more fun
things Felix I I would like to to know
what was the story behind that knapsack
paper how did you come work we work on
it and yeah I can you tell us about it
yeah of course actually it started as my
master thesis so more or less when the
most of the content of the paper is also
my master thesis I opened it a bit of
yeah more of the related work which was
also a big part of my thesis and some
some of the results have not been part
of my thesis but more or less the idea
and the general yeah most of the work is
basically my math assist master thesis
so after I finished the thesis I was I
wrote and paper based on it and I think
the one interesting thing is also that
the knapsack the trunk knapsack for this
mixing is not it's not my my idea it was
I picked up the idea from two papers
which yeah basically in one or two
sentence describe that something like
this could be done but did not really go
into it so yeah this is how I came up
with this idea or why I started working
on this idea and did you follow up on
writing the paper
or what are you what did you move on to
no actually I started after my thesis I
started doing a PhD at the RW th in
authen but after year after one year I
realized that it's not the right
environment for me so I moved on and I'm
now working at and faunal for Institute
which is not at all related to what I've
done before so unfortunately since two
years I'm not working on the topic at
all anymore I see anyone has any general
questions I I have more more in topic
questions now hi well I would like to
know about the test the validation of
these policies if you have published the
the source code for this paper
yes actually I have I have published the
code that I was used to produce the
result of the paper I'm not sure if it's
linked anywhere but I it's a public
repository on jade lab let me paste the
link for you thank you it's great thank
you
most of the difficulties I I encountered
is the deciphering the pseudo code yeah
no the I was just looking into the code
everything's there the in it's written
in rust I don't know if you have
experience with rust but it should be
readable for anybody using who is used
to imperative languages and I think the
interesting part is on the main in the
main source for the distribution dot RS
file
in there are the the different mixing
algorithms that I used yeah Thank You
Lucas your root code for it - and
actually I brought code for it - perfect
so we can we can validate I have one
last question that all you can answer is
that on the paper at the end you wrote
that
however currently our output splitting
algorithm requires knowledge of all sub
transactions using it in a peer-to-peer
network would likely leak information to
all participants
we are already researching a new output
splitting algorithm that mitigates this
problem yes this is exactly the third
mixing algorithm that I developed mostly
at the end of writing the paper so it is
not part of the paper anymore
unfortunately it was finished shortly
after the paper let me see
it's in the code it's this line
basically the idea is that you broadcast
to all participants all the inputs well
you can also do that in a fashion that
you don't know the which input belongs
to which participant and then you can
split your own outputs based on all the
inputs that you that you've seen without
telling anybody all the outputs yeah
that sorry
where are you sharing the links in the
hangouts chat I saved them
okay thank you so that that was all my
questions that only Felix students were
any anyone has any questions to Felix
okay me I go again and about the two
things first I was playing with the
concept for a while and what I do is I
sort the outputs descending by amount
just to it's just an especial case right
and I use two outputs one is the payment
another is the change and I realized
that in this scheme with this
modification well I don't know if is
with this modification only but it
creates for example 1.5 outputs for each
original output for example if I have a
two participant
conjoint with four outputs it creates
six outputs if I have three participants
with two outputs I mean six outputs in
total it creates nine outputs and that I
don't know if you have some comment
about this but go us to to know how many
participants I are in that culture is it
that I'm doing something wrong or or is
just because I'm sorting the their
outputs or or well I can answer my
question just by by calling a bit more
but I don't know if it's something that
you can share with us about that no
that's actually an aspect that I didn't
look into one other aspect that I did
not look into is answering the question
whether looking at multiple knapsack mix
the coins and transactions would allow
you to then again establish stronger
links between inputs and outputs so this
is something I would I would look into
okay and my second question is about the
feet because in the paper you don't
analyze the fee you say basically that
the fee are some kind of noise right so
you cannot match the partitions by
equality because they the input the sum
of the input and the sum of the outputs
are not equal so it will be a bit harder
to to define the transactions but what I
was playing with this concept and I
don't know if you have some idea about
what's the the best way to handle the
the the defeat because if the
participant use the same fee right that
is for example pretty common in for
example in in in wasabi right and then
you know I was actually trying to create
this transactions is ethanol is a son on
wasabi transactions and it's such it's
really bad which is we can go up to one
person plus mine
and he's unreliable interesting well yes
well what I mean is that if if the
coordinator one coordinator that is
coordinating this knapsack transaction
right if everybody uses the same fee
right even the inputs that are bigger
than the outputs so they pay more more
fee if they pay proportional to the to
their transactions then yeah
that gives us a clue about I mean I can
find the sub transactions right the
partitions and and check if the if the
if the fee paid matches the same
transaction or not
so I it is an strong clue for the for
the chain analyzer so do you have Felix
any idea how to handle this what can we
do an idea actually no I my I to analyze
it I implemented an algorithm which it
enumerates all the possible sub sub
assets of the inputs and outputs and
tries to match them so you know I think
I know and I don't know I don't remember
how I did it but is spirited speeded it
up with an bloom filter and I'm I
realized that implementing a fast
algorithm is should probably intuitively
be more difficult if the sums did not
match so and my thinking was that maybe
it does not make the
mathematical problem harder but it makes
it much harder to implement an efficient
algorithm to actually find all the
possible mappings all the possible
partitions yeah that's clear because I'm
suffering with that problem it is it is
really hard because you say okay it has
to match it is have to in a in a range
right it has to okay if it is more or
less this value so yes it's a pain in
the ass but and my mic and you cannot
use and you cannot use a bloom filter of
course so you have to keep it in memory
what is what is even worse but the
question was about how to how can we
make the make the the participants pay a
fee in such a way that it doesn't
provide additional information to the
chain analyzer I'm I'm not sure whether
it actually provides additional
information I would have to think about
it because it would only provide more
information if it would help you
distinguish between subsets that are
more likely the real or mappings that
are more likely the real mappings than
others right agree that it doesn't
provide additional information it makes
it even harder to to do the the analysis
and I I did the analysis with the
precision and the only real difficulty
with the tunnel is how do you set the
precision and what I realized for Norma
Cohen joins you can set the precision as
the mining fee because the mining fee is
the maximum amount one participant can
pay with joint market transactions
it's mining fee plus random I I don't
know what what it should be random
whatever the the going market
transaction agreement was on the fees
that the taker pays for the makers on
massabi it's a mining fee plus 1% and
that produces a bunch of reliability
unreliability of course so so yeah it
it's I don't see how it would provide
more information
now it does it provides more information
in fact I mean if you for example you
know that the the fear rate is I don't
know one yes and you have all this noise
or know the explain it what does it mean
one okay a once at a shipper right
if the fill rate is once at provide for
example so and you use you will see that
the you can take all the the partitions
right and say okay this this the some of
these inputs yes - the some of these
outputs gives you the feel right so that
fee given the the size of the
transaction you know how much it paid a
what is there you don't know right
Sophie you don't know who pay the fee
there are many participants it could be
that only one participant beta fee it
could be that all of them played
together
yes well in that case if only one pay
the fee okay yes it makes sense but in
that case also also is is a problem
because you can say okay if it match
exactly yes then this is one of those
that didn't pay anything - exactly but
if the sum is the sum of the input and
the zone of the outputs then you can say
that this participant did not pay
anything
why wife yes who say that there are many
other sub mappings there could be
possible even if you found one that that
all the dark like that if if you find
other methods that that those are just
as likely as that your first
I think I understand what you mean Lucas
so if all the participants pay exactly
the same fee and we have one mapping
where all the input and the difference
between the inputs and the outputs met
exactly matches this fee then we would
assume that this must be the true
mapping but I'm not sure whether there
would only be one such mapping well yes
but in the in the runs that I think may
I found a lot of mappings but some
mappings have have only two inputs right
and other mappings have 6 inputs yes but
if if I know that they pay 1 Satoshi per
byte and the fee page was next I don't
know yes so I mean I can know which of
those mappings is the real one
because one will be paying exactly one
Satoshi provide and the other one will
be paying a lot less because they have a
lot more inputs so it's a more is a
bigger sub transaction so I know that
sub transaction cannot be the real one
because it's paying the less than and
expected things so you mean when you
have multiple mappings and then the
difference between the inputs and
outputs of sub transactions should be
proportional to the number of inputs and
outputs and then you would know that
it's likely the snapping yes exactly
exactly yeah it could be I mean
obviously I have to add this is more or
less an empirical analysis it's not
really yeah
a mathematical proof of this concept so
I think the idea is really good and I
think it would work combined because of
the reason that it's it's likely
infeasible to find out which mapping is
correct and also difficult to actually
find the mappings once the transactions
get big enough but it's not
yeah it's not provably correct or
provably anonymous in in a more strict
sense I guess okay when one more
question just kind curious and your
analysis
how many sub transactions inputs/outputs
did you did you use I mean did you try
with bigger with a bigger number of
participants with more inputs and more
outputs than those in the in the paper
actually no and the reason was that the
the time it took to to find the mappings
would just grew too much and I didn't it
didn't run on on my workstation I had a
bit bigger server with lots or lots of
RAM and multiple cores I think 64 cores
not obviously you could have a really
much bigger yeah a bigger computing the
computer or server or server farm yeah
for hours for us it was really the case
that it became just too difficult to
find all the or not not difficult but it
took too much time to find all the
mappings yes I know I try with a
participant that yes with sub
transactions and it was running all all
the day and didn't finish so I like can
selected in the process yeah okay thank
you
and if my analysis of the theoretically
theoretical complexity is not completely
wrong then yeah it's I think it the
computing time it takes depending on the
inputs and output really increases by a
lot when you increase the inputs and
output side I have it here but I it's
not written down in a in an easy in easy
way I think to ^ n times n where n is
the which n is set of size n are you
talking about the bare number or your
lower bound estimation my lower bound
estimation well yeah it's I think it
makes sense what I've read on the
internet on Wikipedia that the best best
algorithms known for subset sum so for
solving subset sum is still exponential
yeah so I think if you would I mean in
the the sizes of the of this mixed
transactions in the paper I think should
be only in an Academical setting if you
have if you can automate it and the idea
was you can join an arbitrary and
transactions because the the sum or the
value of the inputs doesn't matter it
doesn't need to be a fixed amount for
each input and then you can create for
each transaction that you do you can
create with other peers for each
transaction in such a corner and
transactional of a huge size if enough
people use the same wallet at the same
time yes we are going into it I'd like
to a an idea of mind at one of the most
frequent question in wasabi was that why
why do we have the hundred anonymity
certain and like that but and and the
reason is because I sent out the emails
and that seemed like them on census data
okay that that should be fine
the pond'rous participant but your lower
bound estimation could actually give us
a mathematic formula to to set a minimum
participants right for for any Cohen
joins okay you you you kind of need at
least this many participants in order to
make he in order to reach this
computational tour nests in deciphering
the Eco in joins does that make sense
guys I think the theoretical bound is
difficult to translate in and concrete
amount of time it needs to find the
partitioning it all it but it really
it's only really good for explaining how
fast it gets more complex or how fast
the time increases that you need to find
a partition depending on the number of
people who participate it's not a
perfect fit but the main problem is that
there must be enough
Virtue's them of what's the minimum
number of participants that we want to
do and that that's why I saw this this
formula your your lower bound estimation
would be actually somewhat useful in in
deciding on that number that we kind of
truth that they arbitrarily or with it
educated guesses I them yes I guess you
could based on the time it takes for
some simple examples you could
extrapolate using that function for more
complex cases with more participants
with more inputs to take part all right
but one more thing I remember in the in
the in the paper you said that if you
spend that one of those outputs in
another knapsack transaction yes the
difficulty could be similar to the one I
mean the problem of finding all the the
mappings is across different across a
chain of not sub transactions
the difficulty also increases similar to
the to the process of mining block 1
mining a chain of blocks right do you
have any additional numbers about that
because I agree intuitively that that is
true but do you have any numbers above
that have you tried that
no no sorry that's something I didn't
try and I'd like to add that intuitive I
think that the difficulty or the the
problem would be that if enough people
would use this kind of transactions and
you had would have a continuous flow of
these transactions which could create
kind of a backlog of coins and
transactions that you need to part to to
find the mappings for which is what I
mean by it the complexity increases when
you have when you use it continuously on
the other hand linking for example two
outputs together it could actually be
more easy if they both appear again as
inputs in at the next corner and
transactions that is one of the one of
the open questions one of the open
problems okay thank you one would like
to chime in it not talked yet
I only have a couple of basic maybe a
little bit stupid questions but are you
guys intending this knapsack going join
as a method of like payment for like
straight-up - father for example on some
service or it's like basic coin joint
like it's the output will come to me
the both outputs like like for for
payments whereas the zero link currently
does coin joins as the as mixing
transactions this is actually the
question I want to ask Felix was you
know if he if he knows anything about
how wasabi it currently works and you
know the the the distinction between a
coin joint for mixing that in a coin
joint for sending and I feel like have
you read this paper I feel like what's
not me being able to send in a coin
showing might might open doors for more
gratis II yet to be honest I didn't know
about wasabi until now because I really
I'm not keeping up with the current
developments on Bitcoin anymore or other
other cryptocurrencies but yeah what was
my my idea was that actually that's the
point of the collapse like mixing that
you can use coins on strength content
transactions for actually performing it
transactions that you want to do not
only for anonymizing coins so you can in
the same step send coins to a third
party and do the mixing okay thanks
one one comment just it is easy for us
if we one day decided to implement
something like this it is easy because
if you mix to yourself you can generate
all the addresses that you need because
you know your keys right and you can
generate your own keys as many as you
want but for payments you need to be
able to generate addresses for someone
else many addresses probably by show
more than and the payment and the change
you need to be able to generate more
addresses so it is not hard to do I
think but it is something that it's not
so easy with with the existing culture
let's say because if I want to pay you
aviv i ask you for one address imagine I
say ok Aviv I want to pay you send send
me ten of your addresses it is not it is
unusual right so we need something
different yes I agree there are
solutions for that like stat addresses
or give me an onion your onion nodes
onion address and we can we could maybe
work it out but it's it's a lot of work
yes
however maybe it's possible to do a
variation of nutsack where you where you
kind of keep the keep the payment as as
as it is but you are only mixing on the
changes it would be an easy easier thing
actually I'm quite sure I've read about
special kinds of Bitcoin addresses where
you can for the receiver of the
transaction generate as many addresses
as you want and I don't remember
was it was kind of like a public/private
key scheme where you can generate new
addresses and only the receiver was able
to use these addresses I guess the only
remaining problem would for the receiver
to notice transactions which are which
contain addresses that belong to him but
I will try to find out what they were
called it's okay I know to both of
dancing has some very serious trade-offs
say if it's one of them or if it's not
then I would like to investigate one is
that addresses the other one the
esthetic rest is you were actually
mentioning that in the paper and the
other one is payment codes is it one of
it I'm not sure I thought it was
something with blind signatures that
that would be actually awesome maybe
maybe I'm remembers remembering
something wrong but I can try to type
try to lube it up and try to find what I
was reading but I thought that that
might not be a problem and anyway I just
like to say that these conversations I
would really like to to make these these
as a learning conversations and not
necessarily how to integrate it or
implement it into a severe or had to do
anything with asabi because there are
like 600 more papers that I want to
review and maybe at the end when when
everything is we learned about
everything that we can you can come up
with something something and then we can
use different techniques from different
papers what what I but my thinking is
right now is that it's just a vogue
idea but if we could figure out if we
could figure out scaling quality if we
could make if we could give a number to
hey we mix this way and this mix is this
efficient if we could kill the
efficiency of the mix if we could tell
how efficient one mixes then we could
come up with a bunch of mixing solutions
and we would know that hey this this
mixing solution give the back best
blockchain space per unanimity gained
number right and what what would be the
unanimity gained but what is this
knapsack paper is is doing pretty bad
that it is I was always thinking about
just breaking the link with how much
anonymity said but this nut sack paper
pointed me that hey you actually can
break the link between the inputs you
can break the link between the outputs
and of course you can break the link
between inputs and outputs so that that
that makes the the the anonymity gained
metric and much better so that's that's
great all right do you guys have any
presentations with presentations here so
I guess at that point I'm going to leave
because it's already quite light here
the address in the paper is not my it's
not a valid email address anymore
I don't receive emails on that address
anymore but if you have any questions
you can contact me at any time I send
you my new email address in the chat so
feel free to ask me if you have any more
questions yeah thank thanks a lot for
for coming it was a pleasure - yeah
thanks for having me it's nice it's
always nice to see that you've done
something interesting yes I'm a big fan
of your work
Thanks so thanks and goodbye maybe until
sometime later all right bye bye
yeah I was thinking about could you
leave showed your presentation again
yeah just give me one quick SEC here
yeah do you have a slide in mind yeah
could you go on the one where is the
inputs and outputs like yeah for for
example this case what determines the
actual numbers of the outputs let's say
that if this wasn't for payments where
there is a exact number or some required
what deterrents these outputs or their
value of them yeah so so the idea is you
would get a more efficient knapsack mix
if you just allowed for infinite outputs
because they would get very small and
then it would take more time to compute
but there's the trade-off that you don't
want to have lots of outputs so the
simple knapsack idea here was just take
regular transactions that have no
special features and for every two
transaction take the larger one the one
with the larger output and break down a
large output into two parts where in
this case the number 31 is the
difference between with your and before
orange-brown
values so in this knapsack method you
all you only add one output for every
two transactions that that combined yeah
okay I'm back yeah yes sorry I lost
connection okay what I want to show you
is yes quality with openness with you
okay
three two pants
I don't know if he's going to her the
number of okay well just going back to
the previous presentation thing I was
just thinking about you know if it
wasn't for payments and there would be
like any kind of set amount that you
would have to reach on as output I
understand that we wouldn't like to like
use too many or break it down into too
many UT exo's but in like in some sense
I think it could kind of work I'm not
sure if it's just too expensive or
something for after why it's like
combining all these UT exo's or
something like that but you know like
breaking it down onto the small as
possible out input that there is and you
know not maybe like like the smallest
one but you know just breaking it down
into smaller and exact the same outputs
you know like you could combine many
inputs and the P would go like a
statically depending on how many inputs
you put in and then it would just you
know give you either like for example a
bigger sum or a smaller something could
be like different kind of connects arcs
going joints I'm not sure if I'm
explaining this correctly do you guys
get any any of that I think I understand
what you're saying there's some there's
some problems with that idea as well I
mean inefficiency is one of them but
their issue that I see with these
knapsack examples is we don't think
about how transactions look like over
over a longer period of time so for
example let's say you have many many
many change outputs if you decide to
then spend many of these change outputs
together in a transaction down the road
it undos all of the privacy gains from
the knapsack for the most part so I
think I think those are those are one
concern is there something else you
wanted to say yeah I'm not sure I mean I
just thought about this thing right now
so maybe I have to just sit down and
think about a little bit more before I
I'll try to like verbalize it but well
another thing was that about mappings
and the computation of that I mean is
that actually necessary for wasabi to do
or is it like just beneficial thing if
it would take too much time for actually
go down on all these mappings I mean
let's say that there would be like let's
say five participants which all are
putting like three different inputs and
yeah for example getting the well X
amount of outputs I'm not sure if it's
only a good thing if the mapping is hard
to calculate my mapping is not necessary
to do in order to be a system it's a but
but what's interesting about calculating
these mappings is that we can actually
see that where are the bottlenecks of
block chain analysis companies so that's
that's I am interested in calculating
the mappings yeah that's what
I was thinking also I mean if we could
just use it as a benefit yeah back back
to the for example the idea that I said
before that Felix actually estimated the
lower lower bound for for the subset-sum
analysis here and we could say that hey
okay we need at least this many inputs
and outputs and if if 10 I think 10 is
pretty let's say if if 10 inputs and
outputs are present then that already
provides computational privacy so we
could set a lower bound for okay yeah we
want to target 10 as the minimum number
of participants or something like that
so that's that's interesting idea
can I add something before I have to run
here it seems like a lot of privacy
benefits would come from having so so
it's right now we've split the mixing
and the sending is two separate features
but it seems like a privacy would be
much stronger if people that weren't
doing mixing could still participate you
know asabi transaction it's just
something that I thought about I'm not
sure I understand sorry yeah I mean so
why that there would be like more people
linked to the coin joints even if they
don't actually use wasabi yeah
is that what if a user just wanted to
send someone money and essentially
wanted to participate in these knapsack
type coin joints for for spending then
that could be a separate service that
can be added to wasabi right like
imagine if the entire blockchain didn't
have transactions but just had lists of
inputs and outputs I think we can agree
that it would be Kahn occasionally very
hard for people to successfully unravel
the entire block of inputs and outputs
so I think that's sort of what I was
thinking about yeah
yes of course it's an even if you don't
do any mixing right more problems there
are read let's say how do you how do you
get over the participants of a block
agree on the field and I the it raises
more questions than it answers I think
one more thing transactions because Aviv
is leaving
before we leaves can we decide on what
what should be our next what should be
next Monday what should we be looking to
you guys have ideas
coughing all right
coin shuffle an idea there are some
papers that were cited by Felix's paper
that I thought were interesting but I
think coin shuffle was one of them Queen
James from crystal vodkas you know
anonymizing the world with human form
she actually enjoyed in mind also
although secure multi-party computation
these which came up in the paper but
I've seen that came up so many times in
so many papers in the coin shuffle paper
to by the way that I'm just as
interested but the heck that we so
anyway any more ideas or decide on these
three now or or both let let's vote on
for these three or or something else in
the mix do you want word
I prefer gone shuffle and there is an
another variant the adult I don't
remember is if it is gone shuffle blasts
blasts or something like that there is
there is coin shuffle plus press and
there is value shava which is coin
shuffle plus plus with confidential
transactions so anyway let's go from
left to right aviv when you shuffle coin
joins to Doku secure multi-party
computation okay Lucas coin shuffle igor
probably yes or yes also green jangsu
Doku but I think is is pretty much the
same that we have discussing today I
find in the the partitions so I don't
know if it brings something new to us
yeah that was kind of my idea there that
we could we could look at someone has
his work on the same topic that's
actually a part of the knapsack paper
and we could we could compare that my
idea so oh there is also sneaker oh it's
knickers - yeah it's knickers can be
true yeah probably sneakers is better
that ventia for because playing traffic
hazard some
some communication is key studies is
pretty hard I don't know if it can be
implemented really so yeah okay
let's start it again then and I will
note how much are the boots on and let's
get to wear it
so we shuffled is from in roughing and
it's about mixing transactions it's
similar to zero link in that sense Cohen
joins to Doku is from vista fat loss'
and it is how do you do non mi Schoen
Joyce
I think it's solving the subset-sum
problem this is this is a small acting
secure multi-party computation I have no
idea what is this but I think it's it's
it's something that we are come back
because it came back many times sneaker
is from Adam Gibson and this is a this
is Co enjoying some some interesting
idea to do Cohen joins okay Aviv Cohen
Schaffer Cohen joins Sudoku secure
multi-party computation sneaker you can
vote for multiple things I think the
question for the sneaker will be
interesting
okay punish of on boot sneaker on vote
because the sneakers monogram yes Nick
or
I cannot hear you
and couldn't couldn't hit anything I'm
gonna head out
I can see your judgment to vote and I'll
read whatever is submitted for next week
perfect see your beef thank you Cheers
thanks thanks an awesome presentation
thanks guys
thank you all right deeper into what I
don't give some does in this topic
because I know the men and yeah I'm
really curious what he's doing
especially with regards to what you guys
are researching so yeah I won't never
secrets alright and the naming is yeah
yeah I like the idea of shuffle and
sneakers
everyone is sanitary probably yeah yeah
yeah yeah are you with us okay I see
what you wrote
you're not familiar with any of all
right well is it very matter what I
wrote is going to be sneaker because
that has four vote and okay so it's
going to be snicker than next X meeting
and Lucas you were saying something that
I disrupted you so go ahead
yeah it's just a comment that those
snaps are instructions for an observer
an external observer it is not easy to
to realize it is a con job because I
mean can be a Buch construction a pay up
pay too many transactions I mean in the
blockchain there are lots and lots and
lots of transactions with more than I
don't know five inputs and then outputs
there are not gonna join right so and so
it is not it is not easy to to know that
that's a conjoined transaction so there
is not a clear finger freedom so you
have to do analyze the transaction and
then you say hey this transaction has a
lot of ambiguity so it has to be current
on transaction but otherwise is is it's
not easy and ok you know you say ok this
is a control transaction and not such
transaction
who who has created that section or how
many participant this has so this this
is not so easy for example in another
way I disagree completely because there
are just so many fingerprints in the
blood that you can tell exactly which
fall has created that transaction by
just dropping at and lock time let's say
you know yes yes yes sir it is possible
but anyway if you for example cannot
know so easily how many participants are
in wasabi this easy because if you count
how many equal outputs are if there are
66 equal outputs then there are 66
participants in this case is a bit
harder so it's
it's something to have in mind by the
way if I can ask a weird question then
what did you mean were no para about
being able to know which while it
created the transaction by the end locks
aren't that different wallets are using
different fees different and lock times
they either use it or not or they either
use a specific number
they might bump the transaction eibar to
do err bf you see there is a set of
features those features sometimes have
like run on uh let's say the fee you
have to decide what fee you will do in
the transaction and if that fee that
exact fee that transaction is being made
with can only be produced with the read
electron-electron is a bad example
because the electron Bitcoin core and
Wasabi's kind of can produce each
other's fees but if that can only be
produced with the electron then then
it's going to be a transaction with the
electron okay so now we figured out that
this is a transaction with electron now
we have to just apply our hell ristic
that what is the likelihood that this
electron is going to create a page to
endpoint transaction so so that's what
I'm saying that there are so many
metadata in the transactions that you
can probably tell what wallet created it
okay yeah thanks for clarifying that I
was fighting a lot against it previously
but I just realized it's it's it not
possible to divide anything because
there is always something
and if I may ask another stupid question
is what exactly is analog time and I
mean I think I've heard about it but I
just don't remember anything or what
does it like conclude
is when that transaction can be mine
basically you say okay this transaction
can be mine right now
can be mine after this vlog hi so
basically that's all we sell fail in the
transaction where you specify when that
transaction can be mine okay yeah all
right
Thanks for for example a Bitcoin core
and electrum are using an N log time
that is in order to discourage fist
knifing which whatever it is it's not on
top of my mind but you know like things
like this or the RBF that's right if you
send the transaction and you have RBF
neighborhood then only that information
that this transaction can do RBF just
okay now look at which wallets can do
RBF and it must be it's probably from
those wallets now if you do an RPF
transaction if you bump the feet then oh
that's a lot more information to expose
because you can only bump the fee from
removing the change then you just
exposed where you are sending the money
which would be exposed by the
transaction chain anyway later on but
you just exposed at that point where you
are sending the money and if the fee
bump has such a specific number that
okay let's say Bitcoin corresponds the
fee with this number or with this period
then then you can you can further narrow
the range of possible wallets that can
can can do that so it gets really really
bad
okay yeah I think I got it and with RBF
you like exposed which one of the
addresses or outputs are like the actual
change yes right that might be the most
obvious one I didn't even have this for
a very long time
but then things just start to click you
know okay yeah okay good to know
all right I have a question you said
about the paper that about that had
information about confidential assets
and mixing or something like that you
mentioned it like five minutes ago
yes I was explained yeah I was
explaining the history of of coin
shuffle it started with coin surfer then
they they came up with a new protocol
that does not require the word that's
called ice mix and they incorporated it
into coin shuffle and they called it
coin shuffle plus plus and then they
figured out how to do coin shuffle with
confidential transactions and that is
called while you shuffle okay send me a
reference think or something on that I
am already done to go in it but it could
be a bit faster and more helpful just
Google values of beta Malaysia are you
interested in question four plus plus
well I'm interested in mixing and
confidential assets involvement in that
because it is well I want to know if
there is something then I can bring 4rg
yeah that's
but something that we could review later
oh okay well that could be the topic
that I might be prepared for so yeah
thanks for explaining that again oh my
good
yeah bring it to next episode and review
see I think there is some some
interesting things to learn from me too
I checked it give you a vote for that
thank you yeah thanks alright do you
guys have anything else
my homework yeah me too
all right then
next next episode is going to be speaker
and yeah thank thanks for coming and I I
feel I will publish it I don't know
where if the recording is good I will
publish it probably the wasabi China and
and and we see like what what are you
thoughts about how was this so far did
you enjoy it
do you have any recommendations out to
or to improve these conversations at
least read the obvious presentation was
pretty damn good
in my opinion I mean like a short recap
of what was what and what's the point of
knapsack so it makes a pretty good like
yeah just a video in itself but of
course also these talks to you know I I
was kind of afraid that Felix are going
is going to leave we have to grab Felix
at the beginning because he's gonna
leave there definitely yes from my my
point to feel the participation of Felix
was great
and so if for sneakers we can't have the
if we can't have Adam here it could be
great too
I will ask him I can't can't promise
feelings didn't promise it to either he
he said he be a try
so that's why I didn't even sent out at
meet or anything hey Felix is going to
be here
because if he's not anyway I will tell
Adam to to come yeah definitely I I hope
he can yeah yeah I think this format was
very good when on the on one hand you
had person within the team who
introduced the brief recap of the
article and then on the other hand he
had the actual author of the article
that could like country but online and
fix mistakes misunderstandings son
everything and also knowing that he's
not working anymore
look Felix is not working in a war for
example for on this topic is also
available because you kind of understand
where it goes and what questions he can
cover and which questions probably
should be covered by someone else
so yeah head and author of paper mister
bit here and of course the discussion
afterwards as always just marvelous
alright guys so if no one has anything
then thank you all for coming and if
this is published and you're listening
it on youtube or something then
definitely everything everything that we
talked about the paper Felix's code or
code everything is going to be in the
description so you can follow up and
maybe change the world by why are you
getting some ideas alright thank you
guys thank you alright
why